Robin G. Blaine

(435) 531-6600 4223 N. Quarterhorse, Enoch, UT 84721 rgblaine@gmail.com https://github.com/Blaine-Rob5000

PERSONAL PROFILE

I became interested in computers as a teenager and taught myself to program in BASIC on a Commodore 64. I even managed to sell a few programs to *RUN Magazine* despite my lack of professional training. After graduating high school with honors, I entered college on a full scholarship pursuing a degree in computer engineering. Due to family challenges, I was forced to drop out of college and enter the workforce. Even though I was unable to further my education at that time, I continued to have a strong work ethic and took on different jobs in the rural community of Louisville, Mississippi, including:

- Material handler at a seatbelt manufacturing plant
- Clerk (and later manager) at a convenience store
- Manager of a check-cashing / payday loan store
- Phone and remote assistance tech for a subcontractor of Gateway computers
- Security guard (a position I held for 10 years)
- Web and social media programmer for a car dealership

For most of that time, I was also the sole, 24/7 caretaker for my elderly mother. Eventually, her condition deteriorated beyond my ability to take care of her and she had to be placed in a professional care facility. Not long after that, I moved to Utah for personal reasons and found part-time employment here. However, due to a medical emergency, I was forced to quit and was unable to work for an extended period. You might say that my career was in the perfect storm. At this point, I decided to return to my passion: computer programming. To that end, I enrolled in a certificate program at Southwest Tech in order to refresh and legitimize my skills.

EDUCATION

Southwest Technical College (Cedar City, UT)

- Technical Certificate in Computer Science (Computer Programming)
- Coursework included:
 - Workplace Relations
 - Computer Literacy
 - Fundamentals of Computer Programming with C++
 - Java Programming
 - Python Programming
 - Swift Programming
- Graduation: April, 2018

Mississippi State University (Mississippi State, MS)

- Studied Computer Engineering
- Did not graduate

Louisville High School (Louisville, MS)

- Graduated with honors
- Took college preparatory classes
- Maintained an A average
- Received numerous awards and full scholarship to Mississippi State University

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Typing (approximately 60 wpm)
- Excellent oral and written communication skills (including spelling, grammar, punctuation, and composition)
- Mathematical proficiency (up to college algebra, geometry, and basic calculus)
- Problem solving and logic skills (including the ability to "think outside the box")
- Attention to detail

EXPERIENCE

Driver for Gannet Publishing (Cedar City, UT)

November 2016 – December 2016 Reason for leaving: Medical Responsibilities:

- Open and lock up office
- Inventory local delivery driver supplies on-hand in office
- Drive company van to St. George to pick up newspapers and any needed supplies
- Inventory newspapers before loading them to ensure the proper number and type are on hand
- Load newspapers onto van via forklift
- Return newspapers to Cedar City, making delivery stops along the way
- Unload newspapers by hand and sort them for local delivery drivers
- Ensure that local delivery drivers get the correct newspapers and needed supplies
- Maintain a clean, neat, and safe work environment

Produce Associate for Walmart (Saint George, UT)

September 2016 – November 2016

Reason for leaving: Seeking work closer to home Responsibilities:

- Stock and price/label produce shelves
- Take down and set up signage and displays for produce section
- Inventory produce storage and inform manager
- Maintain a neat, clean, and safe shopping and work environment
- Provide friendly, courteous, and professional assistance to customers as needed (including de-escalation)
- Handle cardboard and pallet recycling

Web and Social Media Programmer for Bullock Toyota (Louisville, MS)

October 2015 - January 2016

Reason for leaving: Disagreement between manager and owner concerning employee responsibilities

Responsibilities:

- Maintain the company's social media presence on Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram
- Design, maintain, and update websites for sales and repair departments as well as their mobile app
- Design and create advertisements both for their online presence and for print marketing
- Take photographs of cars, employees, and business site for advertisements and web/social media presence
- Provide basic IT support including printers, scanners, PCs, and multiline telephone system
- Answer and direct multi-line telephone calls
- Assist with all manner of maintenance, cleaning, re-organization, assembly, and any other areas as directed by my supervisors and the owners

Security Guard for Vescom Security (Louisville, MS)

October 2005 - October 2015

Reason for leaving: Seeking full-time employment Responsibilities:

- Observe and report on all activities, especially unusual ones
- Monitor the facility via CCTV cameras as well as patrols (both on foot and via electric cart)
- Watch for fires and other hazards

- Received training in first aid, CPR, and fire prevention/fighting techniques
- Maintain logs on all activities and file reports on any incidents
- Check all incoming and outgoing vehicles and shipments to ensure that proper paperwork and inventory is maintained
- Weigh in, weigh out, inspect, and log trucks containing shipments
- Ensure that outgoing shipments are properly loaded and within legal guidelines for weight restrictions
- Greet, assist, and direct employees, vendors, drivers, and visitors as needed in a friendly, courteous, and professional manner
- De-escalate situations involving employees, vendors, and visitors if needed
- Log employees in and out to track time worked
- Answer multi-line telephones, take messages and/or direct calls as needed
- Follow emergency protocols in case of incidents
- Maintain a clean, neat, and safe work environment

REFERENCES

Michael Johnson Aurora, CO (720) 323-9398 mikessuperdeals@yahoo.com

Alan Krajewski Louisville, MS (662) 803-1947 alan.krajewski@gmail.com

Adam Daniel
Noxapater, MS
(662) 552-2326
adamwdaniel@earthlink.net